<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bayesian on A data enthusiast blog - another wannabe &#39;statistician&#39;</title>
    <link>/categories/bayesian/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bayesian on A data enthusiast blog - another wannabe &#39;statistician&#39;</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/bayesian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian vs. Frequentist</title>
      <link>/post/statistics/bayesian/2-inference/bayesian-vs-frequentist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/statistics/bayesian/2-inference/bayesian-vs-frequentist/</guid>
      <description>Here we will look at how a Bayesian and frequentist may go about answering a simple inference question:
BackgroundAs part of our commitment to good medical practice, we decide to conduct a quality assurance audit.
Good Medical Practice
1.13: “You must take steps to mintor and improve the quality of your work”
2.22: “You must take part in systems of quality assurance and quality improvement to promote patient safety”</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elicitation and Conjugacy</title>
      <link>/post/statistics/bayesian/3-elicitation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/statistics/bayesian/3-elicitation/</guid>
      <description>Elicitation is the process of turning an expert’s prior beliefs about one or more uncertain quantities into a probability distribution for those quantities. The term expert simply refers to somebody within the field in which the experiment/analysis is to take place. A successful elicitation process will lead to a prior distribution which accurately reflects the expert’s beliefs. An elicitation is accurate even if the expert’s prior judgements turn out to be completely incorrect!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inference</title>
      <link>/post/statistics/bayesian/2-inference/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/statistics/bayesian/2-inference/</guid>
      <description>In order to have a better understanding of the difference between the frequentist approach and the Bayesian approach to interference let’s use the following example:
Efficacy of RU-486 as an emergency pillA randomized control trial was carried out to ask the question of whether Mifepristone (RU486) can be an effective morning after contraceptive. The study participants were 40 women who came to a health clinic asking for emergency contraception. Method: 20 women were randomly assigned to receive RU-486, and another 20 to receive standard therapy, consisting of high doses of estrogen and synthetic progesterone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>/post/statistics/bayesian/1-introduction/bayesian-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/statistics/bayesian/1-introduction/bayesian-introduction/</guid>
      <description>Bayes Rule in the discrete form, which allows us to calculate the probability of an event A given event B. This is what is called a conditional probability, and we will be working with conditional probabilities a whole lot in this module and also in the remainder of this course. One example of a conditional probability is the false positive or false negative rate of a medical test.
\[P(A|B)= \frac{P(A\bigcap B)}{P(B)}\]</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>