<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Statistics on A data enthusiast blog - another wannabe &#39;statistician&#39;</title>
    <link>/abehzadnia.netlify.com/tags/statistics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Statistics on A data enthusiast blog - another wannabe &#39;statistician&#39;</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/abehzadnia.netlify.com/tags/statistics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Discrete Probability Distribution</title>
      <link>/abehzadnia.netlify.com/post/statistics/probability/probability_discrete_distribution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/abehzadnia.netlify.com/post/statistics/probability/probability_discrete_distribution/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Probability distributions demonstrate the probability of an event. When dealing with discrete data, &lt;strong&gt;probability mass function&lt;/strong&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;event&lt;/em&gt; can come from various distributions. The most important discrete probability distributions are the &lt;strong&gt;Bernoulli&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Binomial&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Poisson&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bivariate Analysis</title>
      <link>/abehzadnia.netlify.com/post/statistics/eda/eda_bivariate_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/abehzadnia.netlify.com/post/statistics/eda/eda_bivariate_analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bivariate analysis&lt;/strong&gt; explore the possible relationship between two variables&amp;rsquo; variability. In view of &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;exploratory&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; focus of EDA, we should refrain from infering based on bivariate analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Univariate Analysis</title>
      <link>/abehzadnia.netlify.com/post/statistics/eda/eda_univariate_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/abehzadnia.netlify.com/post/statistics/eda/eda_univariate_analysis/</guid>
      <description>Univariate analysis focuses on a unfolding the intrinsic statistics of a single variable at hand. This is done as the first step, before jumping into assessing the relationship between variables in our data set.
   Content    Data Type Measure of Center 2.1. Arithmatic Mean 2.2. Harmonic and Geometric Mean 2.3. Median and Mode Measure of Spread 3.1. Variance 3.2. Coefficient of Variance 3.3. Standard Deviation 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probability Function</title>
      <link>/abehzadnia.netlify.com/post/statistics/probability/probability_function/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/abehzadnia.netlify.com/post/statistics/probability/probability_function/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Probability function is the function of a random variable distribution, whose value provides the &lt;em&gt;absolute&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;relative likelihood&lt;/em&gt; of the value of the random variable in the sample.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploratory Data Analysis (introduction)</title>
      <link>/abehzadnia.netlify.com/post/statistics/eda/eda_introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/abehzadnia.netlify.com/post/statistics/eda/eda_introduction/</guid>
      <description>Exploratory data analysis (EDA) is an approach to data analysis that employs tools of descriptive statistics in order to dissect the data. the term exploratory data analysis was coind by John W. Tukey in the 70s.
EDA is a philosophy rather than being statistical technique, in which the statistician takes the role of a detective whose main goal is to unveil the underlying patterns. This is contrary to the classical statistician who acts as a judge instaed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Continuous Probability Distribution</title>
      <link>/abehzadnia.netlify.com/post/statistics/probability/probability_continuous_distribution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/abehzadnia.netlify.com/post/statistics/probability/probability_continuous_distribution/</guid>
      <description>If a random variable is continuous, its probability distribution is called a continuous probability distribution.
Recap  P(X = x) is zero if our X is continuous Continuous probability distributions cannot be tabulated  It&amp;rsquo;s conceptually impossible: we would need to have an infinite number of rows and columns to account for every single P between 0-1, which is infinite. This is well demonstrated in the * Zeno&amp;rsquo;s Paradox *.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>